[Music]
there are a few foundational pillars
that we focused on as a company
the number one absolute number one has
been building consumer trust number two
you know leadership for what I mean
leadership not just from a top line
perspective but it has to be more
sustainable yeah so focus on risk
management focus on all other aspects of
business rather than just Top Line I
think that's that's important third
thing is that we believe we've tried to
stay invested and you know kind of
invested ahead of the time on uh Tech
but you know and this is not just now
over the years we've always been focused
on declarative Innovation yeah and
that's helped us and underpinning all of
this is I think a usual uh issue of
people and culture
[Music]
foreign
you know this was just after the
pandemic all of us got you know locked
down there was Panic All Around
and after a couple of months of the
lockdown we started thinking that this
was probably a good time to think about
inorganic growth we started looking at
opportunities and uh and when you look
at a specific Target bharti AXA was
really a very uh apt Target for us in
terms of size it was roughly about 22
percent of our size
it was doing well it was you know
scaling up but it was still relatively
subscale so if you look at its business
numbers we measure our business and
combine ratio so combined ratio was a
bit elevated but if you split that uh
roughly 78 percent was lost and 42
percent was the expense ratio in a total
combined of 120 yeah which basically
showed you that the business was
underlying business was fine it was just
that it was upscale so expenses were
very elevated thirdly there were certain
uh distribution Partnerships that they
had which was adding to our overall
franchise
and lastly and to me this is very
important we like the the culture and
the team
[Music]
everything was done virtually but just
stepping back to when people think about
this sort of DLC globally a lot of deals
happen in insurance
I think what people uh underestimate is
people often look at financial services
from a balance sheet size perspective
but you look at the volume of
transactions that go through in India is
of a totally different genre yeah so
when you had something like a bharti AXA
and icslumber coming together it's the
probably the largest deal in the
insurance World in India that's ever
happened so far so I think that was one
thing that was sort of I would say very
unique about this deal just another tell
you scale think about it there were 16
000 Distributors that we needed to bring
on together they were 3400 employees
that were in absolutely into the course
of them and bhargav's agenda was always
to observe them absorb them in a very
gentle Manner and you know bring them in
as a family rather than sort of make
them feel that they're new in the
environment that was there I think that
was the second one you just think about
we had about three crore sort of uh
customer letters to send out the 140
branches of bharti that we had to think
about on top of that the product
portfolios were very different
the technology systems were different
they had a different data system we had
a different data system all of that so
as you put it all together uh I would
probably say and I worked on a lot of
global insurance deals uh historically I
would say this was done in a pretty
rapid manner in a very very transparent
manner so building relationships with
people on both sides building trust then
delivering at speed all of us then that
was done in a virtual environment so
yeah I'd say it was pretty unique in
that sense
[Music]
there were three key aspects that we
were particularly focused on which we
felt with the
the three challenges that we had to
address
very very tightly execution at speed in
a context of uncertainty because of
covert and you know unpredictable
lockdowns Etc I think that was probably
challenge number one
secondly once we got the ld1 done the
integration effort that we put in
together thereafter
I think the key objective for us was
that you know we were bringing two
organizations together and our
philosophy was one plus one cannot be
two it has to be much more so we did not
want to uh lose momentum on core
business so we had to ensure the core
business
you know carried on uh you know as BAU
while we get this integration done at
the pace that we set for ourselves so we
didn't want the core business to get
distracted in the either of the
organizations we were in a Services
business and you know when you look at
an acquisition what is it that you are
getting as a value right uh you would
argue that value can be balance sheet
could be customers could be
policyholders could be Distributors but
finally all of that boils down to the
team and the people and you had to
protect the team and give them a sense
of you know comfort and confidence that
you're coming in and you are not you
know there is no winner or loser here we
are coming together as two teams yeah
and uh you know obviously in the part of
the integration process the best man
will win but it will not be driven by
which organization you are coming from
it is purely based on Merit I think
those three were the key uh you know
challenges that we focused on
[Music]
this transaction leaped from us to a
second position in the overall industry
so gave us a market standing Improvement
which would have maybe taken us two to
three as extra time if you hadn't done
this transaction
secondly if you look at the transaction
as I said this was roughly about 20 to
23 percent of her size we paid about
seven point three percent of our stock
to do this transaction so there was a
significant value to be uh you know
delivered if you could get this energy
Synergy benefits that we talked about
and uh you know when two organizations
come in in the same line of business in
a sense there are obviously a lot of
scope for Synergy and you know whatever
we estimated as an organization in terms
of synergy uh the number that we put out
of the market was 200 crores uh we got
the Synergy benefits sooner uh you know
before time okay plus I think they were
very disciplined about the reserving and
their accounting uh which was expected
but we couldn't account for it you know
or anticipated you know fully which has
been an additional benefit
[Music]
foreign
I would say three or four things first
of all you know we asked the right
question to start with and we asked
bharga really what do you want to
achieve out of this and I think I still
remember his words he was very clear
seeing I want a very smooth time-bound
regulatory transparent and beneficial to
all uh deal to happen and that's what I
expect from the postmodger integration
so I think when the leadership is very
clear from both sides and what they're
going to run after what they want to
achieve I think that was one great sort
of stepping stone I think secondly I
think we drew up a joint scorecard and I
think that was pretty good for us that
our joint our scorecards were the same
absolutely the same what for these
scorecards this was all about whether we
can get the synergistic value whether we
can take cost out can we get additional
Revenue how do we settle the people in
how do we look at a new joint business I
actually had a unique team we had a
bunch of Industry Specialists we had
practitioners and then from our
Consulting business in ey and then we
have ey Parthenon we specializes in
postmodger integration so we got a
postmodger integration office as a layer
on top to govern the entire project and
that governance was not only for ey it
was governing a joint team from icsa
Lombard and Eva so that was one joint
team then looking at technology
and looking at all the regulatory
approvals what are the approvals we will
need at what PowerPoint will they come
if there is a delay will we stop our
work or what will we do how will we deal
with that delay and if there's a delay
what's the catch-up mechanism
so and then you know you have various
streams how do they integrate to get the
value out uh that is there I I would say
technology was a very very big part I
think people might undermine that but
when you're doing such a big merger
imagine just you know merging a general
ledger the amount of thinking we have to
do how do we bring it together
[Music]